Guide to the Leonard Solomon Silk papers, 1929-1995 and undated, bulk 1950-1985 RL.01187
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Accession 6096, 1933-1985, and undated, 86 boxes
  - Papers (Box 28)
    - Modigliani, F., Monetary Policy and Consumption - The Linkages via Interest Rate and Wealth Effects in the Federal Reserve MIT-Penn Model, undated 2 copies, xerox (Box 28)
    - Moore, T. G., The Feasibility of Deregulating Surface Freight Transportation, July 1971. 68 pages (Box 28)
    - National Assembly of Social Policy and Development, Inc., Full Agency Information for the National Budget and Consultation Committee, March 1969, 38 pages (Box 28)
    - Nelson, R. R., Big Technology, The Technology Gap, and a Dangerous Policy Pitfall, March 1968, 10 pages (Box 28)
    - Nourse, E. G., What can You do for Your Country? Political Economics for 1976, 22 pages (Box 28)
    - Nye, J. S., The Political Context of Europeans Monetary Integration, 21 pages mimeo, undated (Box 28)
    - Oi, W. Y., On Measuring the Impact of Controls: A Critical Appraisal, 63 pages xerox (Box 28)
    - Okner, B. A., Individual Taxes and the Distribution of Income. October 3, 1972. 41 pages mimeo (Box 28)
    - Okun, A., The Controlled Experiment of 1969. January 19, 1970. 9 pages xerox, 2 copies (Box 28)
    - Statement before the Committee on Banking, Housing and Urban Affairs, July 23, 1975. 15 pages mimeo, Annotated (Box 28)
    - O' Leary, James J. The Outlook for Interest Rates: Can the President's Program be Financed without Placing Serious Strains on the Money and Capital Markets? January 28, 1975. 10 pages typescript (Box 28)
    - Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries, Information and Analysis, Deutche Bank, undated, 27 pages (Box 28)
    - Packer, A. H., Summary of Paper on the Design of Self Stabilizing Economy, April 1974, 4 pages mimeo (Box 28)
    - Park, R. E., The Growth of Cable TV and its Probable Impact on Over the Air Broadcasting, undated, based on more detailed report entitled Potential Impact of Cable Growth on Television Broadcasting, Rand R-587, October 1970, 10 pages mimeo (Box 28)
    - Parkin, M., Wage Behaviour in an Open Economy: Excess Demand, Generalised Expectations and Incomes Policies in the United Kingdom, September 1973, 49 pages xerox (Box 28)
    - Perry, G. L., Current Budget Prospects, December 12, 1969, 7 pages xerox (Box 28)
    - Tax Trauma Ahead? January 1970, 12 pages xerox (Box 28)
    - Peterson, J. L., Concentration of Control and the Price of Television Time. 40 pages (Box 28)
    - Phillips, A., Competitive Policy for Depository Financial Institutions, undated, 33 pages mimeo (Box 28)
    - Chapter V - Technological Change in Air Transportation in the United States, undated, 64 pages xerox (Box 28)
    - Preston, L. E., A Coherent Economy: The Question of Ends and Means. January 1974, 38 pages xerox (Box 28)
    - Primeaux, W. J. Jr., A Re-Examination of the Monopoly Market Structure for Electric Utilities, undated, 66 pages mimeo (Box 28)
  - Papers (Box 29)
    - Research and Policy Committee of the Committee for Economic Development, Further Weapons Against Inflation: Measures to Supplement General Fiscal and Monetary Policies. November 1970, 89 pages xerox (Box 29)
    - Rivlin/Hartman, Budget Issues in Health, Education and Income Maintenance, December 1969, 15 pages xerox (Box 29)
    - Rustow, D. A., Western Europe, the Middle East, and Oil--Or What is Happening to the Emperor's Clothes? 6 pages mimeo (Box 29)
    - Salant, W. S., European Monetary Unification and International Reserves, August 29, 1972. 52 pages mimeo (Box 29)
    - Saulnier, R. J., Notes on the U.S. Economy, August 6, 1973. 2 pages mimeo (Box 29)
    - Scheuer, S. H., How Bold Dare We Be? September 1970, 3 pages photocopy (Box 29)
    - Schnittker, J., Economists and Economic Reporters, undated, 3 pages mimeo (Box 29)
    - Sethuraman, S. V., Urbanisation and Employment in Jakarta. Working papers, Geneva, October 1974 (Box 29)
    - Siegal, I. H., The Kerner Commission Report and Economic Policy, Upjoin Institute, January 1969, staff paper (Box 29)
    - Silk, L. S., The Business Institutions Panel - Impact of Changes in the Information Process on Business Institutions, undated, 24 pages carbon copy (Box 29)
    - Chicago: Champion of the Marketplace, undated, 6 pages annotated (Box 29)
    - Economic Studies at Brookings, April 27, 1970. 4 pages xerox, annotated (Box 29)
    - The Education of Businessmen, supplementary paper, no. 11. December 1960, 2 copies (Box 29)
    - Forecasting Business Trends, undated, 64 pages (Box 29)
    - The French Cassandra, undated, 9 pages xerox (Box 29)
    - Harlan County, University of Wisconsin, May 1938, 48 pages (Box 29)
    - Is there a Lower Middle Class Problem? 6 pages xerox, annotated (Box 29)
    - Labor in Atlantic City, May 30, 1939. 28 pages, annotated, in black folder (Box 29)
    - Marxism and the Decay of Civilization, undated, 22 pages, carbon copy, annotated (Box 29)
    - The Personnel of the National Labor Relations Board. January 1940, 47 pages (Box 29)
    - Reading Diary of Leonard Silk, for Political Parties and Public Opinion (Political Science 122) 1938, 117 pages typescript (Box 29)
    - Simon, H. A., Thinking by Computers, working paper #64, February 18, 1964, 19 pages ditto (Box 29)
    - Silk, L., The Work of Charles F. Ross, paper presented at meeting of New York Chapter, American Statistical Association, March 12, 1958, 4 pages ditto (Box 29)
    - Silk, L., Untitled, undated, 3 pages typescript (Box 29)
    - Sinai, A., Are We Headed for a Crunch? Data Resources Special Studies in Economics, no. 1, July 1973, 47 pages mimeo (Box 29)
    - Sindona, M., International Monetary System and Balance of Payments, November 7, 1972. 30 pages multilith (Box 29)
    - International Monetary and Economic Problems, undated (Box 29)
    - Smallwood, D. E. Competition, Regulation, and Product Quality in the Automobile Insurance Industry, August 15, 1971. An incomplete draft of a paper for the Brookings Institution, mimeograph (Box 29)
  - Papers (Box 30)
    - Smith, S., The Inflation of Steel Prices, Particularly for Steel Conduit and the Need for Government Intervention, undated, 11 pages mimeo. Included in report are correspondence, and attached to front is cover letter (Box 30)
    - Snelden, R. T., Monetary Restraint and Installment Credit, undated, 24 pages photocopy (Box 30)
    - Solo, R. A., The Public Authority and the Market System, undated, 190 pages (Box 30)
    - Solow, R. M., Price Expectations and the Behavior of the Price Level, undated 57 pages xerox (Box 30)
    - Special Research on Trade Policy, Nixon Administration's Dichotomy on Trade Policy Opens Door to Protectionist Lobby Seeking Import Quotas on Textiles, Shoes, 6 pages mimeo undated (Box 30)
    - Reversal of U.S. Trade Policy of 36 Years by Congress Feared; Major Effect on Consumers, Exports, Foreign Relations Seen, undated, 10 pages mimeo (Box 30)
    - Staff of the World Bank Group, Additional External Capital Requirements of Developing Countries. International Development Association, March 1974, 19 pages (Box 30)
    - Taubman, P., Monetary Policy and Consumption - Or a Chain is Only as Strong as Its Weakest Link? undated 1 copy 16 pages, photocopy and 1 copy 18 pages, xerox copy (Box 30)
    - Taxation with Representation, A Public Interest Taxpayers' Lobby, Evaluation of Proposals for Consideration in First Phase of Tax Reform. undated 15 pages multilith (Box 30)
    - Tilton, J., The International Diffusion of Technology, A Case Study of the Semiconductor Industry, April 1970. 5 pages photocopy. Also preliminary drafts:
      - Chapter I, Introduction, 6 pages (Box 30)
      - Chapter II, The Semiconductor Industry, 21 pages (Box 30)
      - Chapter III, The Rate of Diffusion, 47 pages (Box 30)
      - Chapter IV, United States, 83 pages (Box 30)
      - Chapter V, Europe, 65 pages (Box 30)
      - Chapter VI, Japan, 42 pages (Box 30)
      - Chapter VII, Conclusions, 17 pages (Box 30)
    - Trezise, P. H. Monetary Union and U.S. Policy Toward Europe, September 15, 1972. 10 pages mimeo, annotated (Box 30)
    - Triffin, R., Prospects for International Monetary Reform, December 1972, 13 pages mimeo, annotated (Box 30)
    - Turner, D.F., Legal and Related Problems in the Collection and Use of Private Economic Data, undated, 13 pages, ditto (Box 30)
    - Tyler, G., Economic Factors in Group Life, paper prepared for the Task Force on Group Life in America, June 1, 1971, 31 pages mimeo (Box 30)
    - Wallich, H. C., From Multiplier to Quantity Theory, May 23, 1975, 26 pages mimeo (Box 30)
    - Weidenbaum, M. L., Limitations of the Full Employment Budget, March 1974, 3 pages mimeo (Box 30)
    - Weintraub, S., On Eliminating Inflation and Outmoded Economic Doctrines, undated, 9 pages, 2 copies (Box 30)
    - On ending the Inflation Unemployment Tangle, undated, 3 pages xerox (Box 30)
    - Weiss, L. W., An Evaluation of Antitrust in the Electric Power Industry, 55 pages mimeograph (Box 30)
    - Whiting, B., The Suddenly Remembered American, draft, undated (Box 30)
    - World Bank Paper, Land Reform, July 1974 (Box 30)
    - Rural Development Series, Agricultural Credit, August 1974 (Box 30)
    - Vanek, J., A Proposal for a Study to Implement a Fully Self Managed Industrial Enterprise in the United States, undated, 5 pages mimeo (Box 30)
    - Appendix, undated, 53 pages photocopy (Box 30)
    - Appendix to Chapter 23, The Full Employment Budget, undated, 5 pages (Box 30)
    - Arab Investments: Threat or Boon for the West, undated 12 pages (Box 30)
  - Papers, no authors (Box 31)
    - Chapter I, Introduction, undated 16 pages photocopy (Box 31)
    - Chapter 7, Summary and Conclusions, undated 35 pages (Box 31)
    - Controlling the Inflation Process, undated 1 pages mimeo (Box 31)
    - Epilogue - Some Evidence of the Model's Ability to Capture Monetary Effects on Consumption and on the Reliability of the Reduced Form Approach, undated 12 pages photo copy, annotated (Box 31)
    - Lecture 1: The Logic of Economic Policy, undated 2 pages incomplete preface, 163 pages, undated (Box 31)
    - Problems of United States Economic Development, Vol. 2, Committee for Economic Development, volume of fifty papers, May 1958 (Box 31)
    - Program of Participation and Labor Managed Systems, Statement of Plans for 1973-1976, undated 14 pages mimeo (Box 31)
    - Proposed Study of Antitrust Policy, December 9, 1969, 12 pages mimeo (Box 31)
    - Public Forum on Economic Issues, undated 10 pages (Box 31)
    - Regulation, Competition and the Computing Industry: A Research Proposal. Preliminary draft, August 20, 1969, 12 pages photocopy (Box 31)
    - Review: Henry Hazlitt, the Failure of the New Economics, 7 pages ditto, annotated (Box 31)
    - Rule 394 and the Public Interest, undated 11 pages multilith (Box 31)
    - Wage and Price Policy for Monetary Stability, December 19, 1969, 13 pages typescript (Box 31)
    - Working papers...Commission on the year 2000 of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, Vol III. Questions and Caveats about Forecasting the Political Structure and Vol. V, Intellectual Institutions, the Life Cycle, and International System, undated (Box 31)
    - Chapter Two, The Costs of Short Haul Air Service (Box 31)
    - Chapter Three, The Demand for Short Haul Air Service (Box 31)
    - Chapter Four, The Local Service Experiment (Box 31)
  - Papers (Box 32)
    - [Chapter 5 not listed in original inventory.] (Box 32)
    - Chapter Six, Transition to Trunkline Status (Box 32)
    - Chapter Seven, The Future of Short Haul, Low Density Air Service (Box 32)
    - Chapter IX, Construction (Box 32)
    - Lost, unidentified or incomplete pages from papers, 4 items (Box 32)
  - Miscellaneous Print Material (Box 32)
    - Public Policy, Vol. XIX, No. 4, Fall 1971 (Box 32)
    - Saturday Review, Vol. LV, No. 4, January 22, 1972 (Box 32)
    - Saturday Review, Vol. 1, No. 10, January 26, 1974 (Box 32)
    - Saturday Review, Vol. 2, No. 25, September 6, 1975 (Box 32)
  - Photographs (Box 32)
    - Photos of Leonard Silk, 84 items (Box 32)
      Sizes range from 1x1" to 9x12". Images include informal settings, graduations, military occasions, professional meetings, and photos of Silk with notables such as President Lyndon Johnson.
    - Photos of others, identified (Box 32)
      Sizes range from 2x2" to 8x10". Images portray friends and family, as well as important academic, public, and political figures such as Lord Halifax, Orson Wells, Jan Smuts, Paul Volcker, and Nelson Rockefeller.
    - Photos of others, unidentified (Box 32)
      Sizes range from 2x2" to 8x9". There are also two negatives. Photos include: military, children, informal settings, UN and other meetings, and snapshots of groups at meetings and dinners taken in Madison, WI.
  - Press Releases (Box 33)
    - Statement by Joel Dean to U.S. Senate Antitrust and Monopoly Sub Committee, A Positive Program for Antitrust, proposed testimony of Joel Dean, for release September 10, 1965 (Box 33)
    - Press releases from World War II written by Leonard S. Silk, 13 items (Box 33)
    - American Enterprise Institute, for immediate release, July 15, 1970 (Box 33)
    - American Importers Association, New York, March 21, 1972, noon embargo (Box 33)
    - American Petroleum Institute, Address for presentation at a General Session during the 1972 Annual Meeting of the American Petroleum Institute, Chicago, Illinois. November 13-14, 1972, An Action Program for U.S. Energy Policy During the Seventies, by Walter J. Levy, for release after 10:00 (CST), November 14 (Box 33)
    - American Retail Federation, Congressional Drive for Textile, Shoe Quotas Would Raise Prices on Clothing, Footwear, and Threaten Illinois' $3 billion Exports. For immediate release, no date (Box 33)
    - Bank of America News, for further information contact: Jay DeBow and Partners, Inc., A Syndicate of International Commercial banks lead by Bank of America Has Entered the Market with $150 million Seven Year Credit for the Republic of Ecuador, For immediate release, undated (Box 33)
    - Boards of Governors, 1970s Annual Meeting, Copenhagen, press release No. 3, Statement by Pierre-Oaul Schweitzer, Chairman of the Executive Board and Managing Director of the International Monetary Fund, in Presenting the Twenty-fifth Annual Report of the Executive Directors to the Board of Governors of the Fund, hold for release September 21, 1970 (Box 33)
    - The Brookings Institution New Release, Contact Jim Farrell, Brookings Study Probes Consequences of Higher World Oil Prices, release, November 24, 1975 (Box 33)
    - Chem Systems, Inc., Chem Systems Names Corporate Planning Manager, for immediate release, undated (Box 33)
    - Committee for a National Trade policy, U.S. Arrogance in Vetoing Schweitzer Reappointment Deplored, for release, September 27, 1972 (Box 33)
    - Congress of the United States, Joint Economic Committee, Senator Proxmire Announces Hearings on the 1968 Economic Report of the President, for immediate release January 31, 1968 (Box 33)
    - Congressional Quarterly News Service, White House Preparing to Propose Restructuring of Social Programs, immediate release, July 23, 1975 (Box 33)
    - Congressional Quarterly News Service, Nixon's Chief Tax Aide Now Business Lobbyist, for immediate release, August 14, 1973 (Box 33)
    - Corporate Headquarters, Failure to Guarantee Lockheed Loan Would Mean $20 Billion Monopoly, for release June 28, 1971 (Box 33)
    - Data Resources, Inc. for release, December 31, 1969 (Box 33)
    - The Department of the Treasury News, Remarks of the Honorable Eugene T. Rossides Assistant Secretary of the Treasury for Enforcement and Operations before the Eighty-Ninth Annual Banquet Phi Delta Phi of Columbia Law School, International House, Statement entitled the Nixon Administration's Reform Program to Combat the Illegal Use of Secret Foreign Bank Accounts, for release upon delivery (April 23, 1970) (Box 33)
    - Economic Department, contact: Douglas Greenwald, Chief Economist Industrial Operating Rate Continues Dip, for release August 23, 1974 (Box 33)
    - Economic Department, Industrial Operating Rate Turns Up in July: Mining Stages Strong Push, for release August 24, 1973 (Box 33)
    - European Community Press Release, European Community Information Service, no 18/1975. EC Delegation to Hold Talks at UN Monday, for immediate release, November 15, 1975 (Box 33)
    - Evaluation Magazine, contact: Wy Spano, Heller Says more Taxes Possible to Fund H Man Services, for immediate release, July 3, 1974 (Box 33)
    - Executive Office of the president, Council of Economic Advisers, Remarks of Hendrik S. Houthakker, Member, Council of Economic Advisers at Louisiana State University, May 4, 1970. For Release on delivery May 4, 1970 (Box 33)
    - Statement of Herbert Stein before the Joint Economic Committee Subcommittee on Economy in Government Hearings on Changing National Priorities, June 15, 1970, for release upon delivery (Box 33)
    - Federal Home Loan Bank of San Francisco, for release September 12, 1974 (Box 33)
    - Federal Reserve Bank of New York, No. 1079, Economic Health of Nation and New York City Requires Major Shift in Attitudes, Volcker Warns, for release E.S.T. November 12, 1975 (Box 33)
    - Federal Reserve Press Release, March 11, 1970, Treasury and Federal Reserve Foreign Exchange Operations. Another release June 29, 1970 (Box 33)
    - From the office of Senator Edward M. Kennedy of Massachusetts, Senator Kennedy Urges Tax Relief and Tax Reform, Including End to Syndicated Tax Shelters, for immediate release, June 10, 1974 (Box 33)
    - From the Office of Senator Jacob K. Javits, Contact: Peter Teeley, Javits/Humphrey Propose Legislation for Long-Term Economic Planning for immediate release, May 12, 1975 (Box 33)
    - Headquarters, United States Forces in Austria, Vienna, April 15, 1946, for release at 1900 hours (Box 33)
    - Initiative Committee for National Economic Planning, Statement by Wassily Leontief, Harvard University, Nobel Laureate in Economics, Co-Chairman of The Initiative Committee for National Economic Planning, for release May 12, 1975 (Box 33)
    - Statement by J. Irwin Miller, Chairman of Cummings Engine Col, for release May 12, 1975. Statement by Leonard Woodcock, president of the UAW, Co-chairman of the Initiative Committee for National Economic Planning, for release May 12, 1975 (Box 33)
    - International Finance Corporation, World Bank Affiliate Invests $122 Million, Helps Creat 19,000 New Jobs in Developing Countries During Fiscal Year, for release September 17, 1970 (Box 33)
    - Mel Adams and Associates, Inc. for: Salomon Brothers, Contact: Charles Brophy, for release, November 21, 1975 (Box 33)
    - Morgan Guaranty Trust Company of New York: for release March 25, 1974, for release May 23, 1974, and for release August 23, 1974 (Box 33)
    - Morris Mendelson, University of Pennsylvania, The Automated Trading System, for release immediately, undated (Box 33)
    - Michael W. Moynihan, Public Affairs Consultants, ECAT Will Lead Campaign for Multinational Companies, for release February 24, 1972 (Box 33)
    - National Foreign Trade Council, Inc., for immediate release, November 14, 1972 (Box 33)
    - New Orders Index, McGraw-Hill Publications Company, contact: Douglas Greenwald, for release November 21, 1975 (Box 33)
    - New York University News Bureau, Bob Terte, for release April 26, 1973/ (Box 33)
    - News, U.S. Department of Labor, Bureau of Labor Statistics, BLS Report Examines Employment in Perspective, for release June 15, 1970. 2 copies (Box 33)
    - News United States Railway Association, contact: Alex Bilanow and Bob O'Rourke USRA Issues Supplemental Report, for release September 19, 1975 (Box 33)
    - USRA Board Approves Terms of Chessie Acquisitions, for release November 6, 1975 (Box 33)
    - Clarification of News Release, November 18, 1975 (Box 33)
    - Office of Senator Williams Proxmire, Wisconsin, for release November 17, 1975 and November 19, 1975 (Box 33)
    - Probe International, Contact: Evelyn Hersh, Soviet Commercial Penetration in Far East is New Threat to U.S. Trade and Investment in Region, for release November 20, 1975 (Box 33)
    - Public Affairs Department (CITICORP) from: John M. Williams, Consumer has Hang Dog Outlook on Economy, Bank Survey Shows, for release November 17 1975 (Box 33)
    - Public Interest Economics Center, contact: Robert Waldrop, for release December 28, 1972 (Box 33)
    - Regional Plan Association, news release No 1180, for release March 19, 1973 (Box 33)
    - Remarks of Eugene Miller, New York Stock Exchange to the San Diego Union-Tribune Investors Clinic, May 28, 1970, for release May 28, 1970 (Box 33)
    - Remarks of Richard M. Nixon, New York, carbon copy undated (Box 33)
    - Remarks of Senator Humphrey at May 12 Press Conference on Balanced Growth and economic Planning Act of 1975, for immediate release, May 12, 1975 (Box 33)
    - Taxation with Representation and the Tax Action Campaign, A Public Interest Taxpayers' Lobby, Tom Reese or Tom Field, Ways and Means Committee Ranked on Reform, for release November 17, 1975 (Box 33)
    - The Trilateral Commission, Governments Should Actively Move Forward on stalled Trade Negotiations, Counsels Trilateral Task Force, News release September 16, 1974 (Box 33)
    - United States - Japan Trade Council, Japan Unilaterally Slashes Tariffs on 238 Items, Eliminates More Quotas, Cuts Auto Taxes, to Assist U.S. Passages of Gold Bill. For immediate release. Also attached is comments on H.R. 10914/S 2592 (Burke-Hartke Bill) (Box 33)
    - Vance Hartke United States Senator News, Hartke Condemns Attempts to Suppress Public Broadcasting Programming, for release November 19, 1975 (Box 33)
    - White House Economic Program Fact Sheet, June 12, 1973, embargoed for release until 8:30 p.m (Box 33)
  - Press Summary, New York Times (Box 33)
    - June 1970 (Box 33)
    - September 9, 1971 (Box 33)
    - November 18, 1975 (Box 33)
  - Proceedings and Seminars (Box 33)
    - Alliance Capital Management Corporation, Tenth Annual Corporate Pension Conference, New York City, October 30, 1973 (Box 33)
    - American Bankers Association, Proceedings of a Symposium on Money, Interest Rates and Economic Activity, 1967 (Box 33)
    - American Bankers Association, Proceeding of a Symposium on the Federal Budget in a Dynamic Economy, April 2, 1968, 2 copies (Box 33)
  - Proceeding and Seminars (Box 34)
    - American Life Insurance Association, Life Officers Investment Seminar, 1974 (Box 34)
    - Ballotti, Geno A., Managing Editor, Daedalus, Proceedings of the Conference on Business and Society. Sponsored by Deadalus and the Amos Tuck School of Business Administration at Dartmouth College, 1966 (Box 34)
    - Corporation Service Seminar folder, The Changing Pattern of the International Monetary System, May 15-17, 1972 (Box 34)
    - Faculty Seminar on European Community Studies, The City University of New York, December 6, 1971 (Box 34)
    - Gardner, Richard N. New Structures for Economic Interdependence, The Proceedings of an International Conference with a Report by Richard N. Fardner, 1975 (Box 34)
    - Inflation Control, Myth or Reality? Proceedings of a Special Feature Session, 74th Congress of American Industry, New York, December 5, 1969 (Box 34)
    - Long Island University, How to Operate Under the Wage-Price Freeze, Irving Schreiber, Editor, Based on a Tax Conference of the Center for Tax Studies, C.W. Post College, Long Island University, 1972 (Box 34)
  - Reports (Box 36)
    - Automation, Report from the President's Advisory Committee on Labor Management Policy, Washington, D.C. January 11, 1962 (Box 36)